Register of the Edward Geary Lansdale papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound Recordings, 1951-1975
  - Senior Liaison Office staff and friends, 1965-1975
    - Tape 27, Vietnam, 1966 December 11
      - 6. "Advisory Team 54," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 7. "Answer To The Green Beret," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 8. "Proud American," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 9. "Six Clicks," Hershel Gober (English)
    - Tape 28, Vietnam, 1966 Fall
      This is more of Hershel Gober's music, titled by General Lansdale, "Gober on Departure." Gober left Vietnam in the fall of 1966. In between musical numbers, Gober discusses his experiences in Vietnam.
      - 1. "Goodbye Travis Air Force Base," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 2. "Proud American," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 3. "Saigon Warrior," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 4. "Here Am I," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 5. "Picture of a Man," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 6. "Tropic Rain," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 7. "Look Over My Shoulder," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 8. "Six Clicks," Hershel Gober (English)
    - Tape 29, Vietnam, 1966 Fall (Box 87)
      This is a continuation from tape 28.
      - 1. "The Forgotten Man," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 2. "Beneath the Willow Tree," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 3. "Birth of a Nation," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 4. "Proud American," Hershel Gober (English)
        The last half of this tape contains songs by Pham Duy.
      - 5. "Let's Build a New Life Hamlet," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 6. "To Sing Often Is Better than to Sing with a Good Voice," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 7. "Wearing the Black Costume," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 8. "A Cup of Rice Is a Cup of Sweet and a Cup of Blood," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 30, Vietnam, 1966
      This tape and the next one (31) bring together songs by a variety of people, Vietnamese and American, who gathered in General Lansdale's Saigon quarters at 194 Cong Ly. Lansdale and other members of the Senior Liaison Office Staff selected folk songs and, with a narration written by Lansdale and read by Hank Miller (also on the SLO staff), included them in this recorded report entitled, "In the Midst of War."
      According to Lansdale, this complilation of songs was made with Washington officials in mind. Copies of the tapes were sent to President Johnson, Vice President Humphrey, Secretary of State Dean Rusk, Secretary of Defense Robert MacNamara, Senator Fulbright, and National Security Advisor Walter Rostow. (Ambassador Lodge and General Westmoreland also received copies.) Lansdale hoped to give the policy makers a "feel" for the people involved in Vietnam, but he received only formal acknowledgements and "had a sneaking feeling" that the policy makers never listened to the contents of the tapes.
      Many of the artists heard on other tapes -- Pham Duy, Steve Addis, Hershel Gober, Sam Wilson, and Jim Bullington, among others -- are included in this report. There are Vietnamese and American folk songs and new songs written by servicemen in Vietnam. General Lansdale's friend, the Vietnamese songwriter Pham Duy, appears throughout the tape program. There are 51 songs, including some repeats.
      A list of the songs, and a copy of the narrative part of the program, accompanies this register in Appendix B.
    - Tape 31, Vietnam, 1966
      This is a continuation from tape 30.
    - Tape 32, Vietnam, 1967
      This is a tape of a visit to 194 Cong Ly by John Steinbeck. He listens to Pham Duy and Steve Addis, and Steve Addis talks from time to time about Vietnamese music. According to Addis, there are three types of Vietnamese songs: folk, classical, and "heart" songs. Most of Pham Duy's songs are "heart" songs.
      This is the first of a series of tapes: 32, 33, and 34.
      - 1. "Vietnam, Vietnam," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 2. "The Wounded Soldier," Pham Duy and Steve Addis (English and Vietnamese)
      - 3. "Rain on the Leaves," Pham Duy and Steve Addis (English and Vietnamese)
      - 4. "To Sing Often Is Better than to Sing with a Good Voice," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 5. "A Cup of Rice Is a Cup of Sweet and a Cup of Blood," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 6. "Clementine," Pham Duy and Steve Addis (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 33, Vietnam, 1967
      This is a continuation of the Steinbeck visit. It begins with Pham Duy talking about American protest songs -- "they only protest against us" and never against the other side. His songs are also protest songs, he says, but against the North Vietnamese.
      - 1. "On Behalf," Pham Duy (Vietnamese), with Steve Addis giving a translation at the end of each verse
      - 2. "Suc May Ma Buon," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
        Pham Duy, Steve Addis, and General Lansdale talk about the "tone" of Vietnamese songs. Since Vietnamese is a tonal language, its words have almost musical ups and downs. If a word has a rising accent, or a lowering accent, when set to music it would need appropriate rising or lowering tones in the song. Pham Duy comments that Vietnamese songs are usually sad and defeated-sounding. Although the next song has a different, uplifting tone, it nevertheless caught on.
      - 3. "Youth Song," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
        Pham Duy talks about trying to "entertain" a people which has endured 25 years of war. He says that the duty of an artist is to "harmonize" society. It is necessary to leave the city and work in the villages.
        General Lansdale reminisces about the 1965 Thanksgiving dinner with General Thang. Thang told Pham Duy to write some new songs, because he hadn't written a good song since 1948 (when "Youth Song" was composed).
      - 4. "Carrying Rice," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
        This is an example of a song to mobilize the people.
      - 5. "Dirty Old Town," Steve Addis (English)
        After this song, Steve Addis discusses Vietnamese music, expecially the music of North Vietnam. Lansdale comments on a poem, written by a Viet Cong who had been killed in a battle; the poem was to his mother. Pham Duy set it to music and it was heard all over South Vietnam. Lansdale felt it was effective counter-propaganda, because it was critical of the Viet Cong.
        Steve Addis talks about Hue, which is the "cradle of Vietnamese music." He talks about the night that he and Pham Duy recorded on the Perfume River, in Hue, in a boat. This recording is in this collection (tape # 52).
    - Tape 34, Vietnam, 1967
      This is a continuation (and a partial repeat) from tape 33. This is the last tape of the Steinbeck visit.
    - Tape 35, Vietnam, 1967 May 14
      This tape was recorded at 194 Cong Ly. It is labelled "Hank Miller Farewell" and is a tape of a gathering of friends, with entertainment provided by Pham Duy and group singing. The recording is continued on tape 36.
      - 1. Guitar music
      - 2. Flamenco guitar music
      - 3. Flamenco guitar music
      - 4. "Youth Song," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 5. "Vietnam, Vietnam," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 6. "Rain on the Leaves," Pham Duy (Vietnamese and English)
      - 7. "The Wounded Soldier," Pham Duy (Vietnamese and English)
      - 8. "Clementine," Pham Duy and group (Vietnamese and English)
      - 9. "Plaisir d'Amour," Pham Duy and group (Vietnamese, French, and English)
      - 10. "Suc May Ma Buon," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 36, Vietnam, 1967 May 14
      This is a continuation from tape 35.
      - 1. "To Sing Often Is Better than to Sing with a Good Voice," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 2. "The Enemy Is No Man," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 3. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy and group (Vietnamese)
      - 4. "The Wounded Soldier," Pham Duy (Vietnamese and English)
      - 5. Flamenco guitar music
      - 6. Flamenco guitar music
      - 7. "Vietnam, Vietnam," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 37, Vietnam, 1967 July 27
      This is a tape of the wedding reception given by Lansdale after the marriage of Trinh Minh Nhut and Pham Thi Khonh Chi. It was recorded at 194 Cong Ly. Trinh Minh The's widow asked General Lansdale to represent her family at the marriage of her oldest son to General Chi's daughter. All of the men of her family had died. Evidently Trinh Minh The had spoken of General Lansdale as his "brother," so she asked Lansdale to do the honors.
      There is an introduction by Cal Mehlert, a career Foreign Service officer who speaks both Vietnamese and English. He joined the SLO in 1967-1968, serving several tours of duty. He also spoke Chinese and served as an interpreter during Nixon's visit to Peking.
      - 1. "To Sing Often Is Better than to Sing with a Good Voice," Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese)
      - 2. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese)
      - 3. "Early Morning in the Woods," Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese)
      - 4. Vietnamese song, woman soloist (Vietnamese)
      - 5. Vietnamese song, two women (Vietnamese)
      - 6. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy and two women (Vietnamese)
      - 7. "Suc May Ma Buon," Pham Duy and two women (Vietnamese)
      - 8. "Vietnam, Vietnam," Pham Duy and the Villagers (Vietnamese)
      - 9. "Hat Hoi Trang Ram," two women (Vietnamese)
      - 10. "Rain on the Leaves," Pham Duy and two women (Vietnamese)
      - 11. "Clementine," Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese and English)
      - 12. "Red River Valley," two women and The Villagers (Vietnamese and English)
      - 13. "Hat Hoi Trang Ram," Pham Duy and two women (Vietnamese)
      - 14. "Fishermen's Song," Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 38, Vietnam, 1967 August 22
      This is a tape of a gathering at 194 Cong Ly, evidently including Prime Minister Ky and General Thang. It begins with General Lansdale telling a joke. In the background is guitar music and humming ("The Rain on the Leaves"). After a while Pham Duy begins to sing. When the music ends, General Lansdale is heard commenting upon the earlier visit by John Steinbeck. This recording is continued on tape 39.
      - 1. "Rain on the Leaves," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 2. "Arirang," Pham Duy (Korean)
      - 3. "Clementine," Pham Duy (Vietnamese and English)
      - 4. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 5. "Autumn in Paris," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 6. "On Behalf," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 39, Vietnam, 1967 August 22
      This is a continuation from tape 38.
      - 1. "Youth Song," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 2. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 3. "The Wounded Soldier," Pham Duy (Vietnamese and English)
      - 4. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 5. "Suc May Ma Buon," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 6. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 7. "Greensleeves," Pham Duy (Vietnamese and English)
      - 8. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 9. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 10. "The Wounded Soldier," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 11. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 40, Vietnam, 1967 September 18
      This is a recording of a "Goodbye to Ambassador and Mrs. Lodge and Ambassador and Mrs. Porter" (Part I). The tape was made at 194 Cong Ly. It is the first in a series of three tapes: 40, 41, and 42.
      - 1. "Rain on the Leaves," Pham Duy (English and Vietnamese)
      - 2. "Suc May Ma Buon," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 3. Revolutionary Development song, Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 4. "In the Evening by the Moonlight," Sam Wilson (English)
      - 5. "On Top of Old Smokey," Ambassadors Lodge and Porter (English)
      - 6. "Old 97," Ambassadors Lodge and Porter (English)
      - 7. "Bill Bailey," Sam Wilson (English)
      - 8. "Jack of Diamonds," Sam Wilson (English)
      - 9. "Cigarettes and Whiskey," group (English)
      - 10. "Old Man You Oughter," Sam Wilson (English)
      - 11. "Little Brown Jug," Sam Wilson (English)
      - 12. "Summertime," Sam Wilson (English)
      - 13. "Saigon Nights," Sam Wilson (English)
    - Tape 41, Vietnam, 1967 September 18
      This is a continuation from tape 40.
      - 1. "Love Letters in the Sand," Sam Wilson (English)
      - 2. "Invitation to Dance," Sam Wilson (English)
      - 3. "She's a Personal Friend of Mine," Ambassador Lodge (English, French, German)
      - 4. "Who Stole the Jam?," Ambassador Lodge (English)
      - 5. "You Are My Sunshine," Sam Wilson and group (English)
      - 6. "Clementine," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 7. "Red River Valley," Pham Duy and Sam Wilson (English and Vietnamese)
      - 8. "In the Evening by the Moonlight," Ambassador Lodge and group (English)
      - 9. "Sheik of Araby," Sam Wilson and group (English)
      - 10. "Lazy River," Sam Wilson and Ambassador Lodge (English)
      - 11. "Oh Sammy," Ambassador Porter (English)
      - 12. "Ten Pretty Girls," Ambassador Porter (English)
      - 13. "I'll Be Glad When You're Dead," Ambassador Lodge (English)
      - 14. "Miss Otis Regrets," Ambassador Lodge (English)
      - 15. "To Sing Often Is Better than to Sing with a Good Voice," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 42, Vietnam, 1967 September 18
      This is a continuation from tapes 40 and 41.
      - 1. "On Behalf," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 2. "The Lover of the Cambo," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 3. "Vietnam, Vietnam," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 4. "Whiffenpoof Song," Sam Wilson (English)
      - 5. "Oh Cherchonia," Sam Wilson (English and Russian)
      - 6. "Saloon," Ambassador Lodge (English)
      - 7. "Mississippi Mud," Ambassador Lodge (English)
      - 8. "Truckin' on Down," Sam Wilson (English)
      - 9. "Ain't She Sweet," Ambassadors Lodge and Porter (English)
      - 10. "Hard Hearted Hannah," Ambassador Lodge (English)
      - 11. "There Are Blues," Ambassador Lodge (English)
    - Tape 43, Vietnam, 1967 October 25
      This is a recording of a gathering at 194 Cong Ly. It begins with crowd noise and a Vietnamese speaker, then there is a translation into English. The speaker introduces Nguyen Cao Ky as a "youth leader" and "singer who comes from Hanoi." Ky used to sing with the youths he led in North Vietnam. Pham Duy sings because Ky is too shy. This recording is continued on tape 44.
      - 1. "Youth Song," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
        Scope and Contnets note
        A group of singers from Saigon is introduced (their leader is "Mr. Yet").
      - 2. "To Sing Often Is Better than to Sing with a Good Voice," Saigon group (Vietnamese)
      - 3. Cadre song, Saigon group (Vietnamese)
      - 4. Cadre song, Saigon group (Vietnamese)
      - 5. "Red River Valley," Saigon group (Vietnamese)
      - 6. "Rain on the Leaves," Saigon group (Vietnamese)
      - 7. Vietnamese song, Saigon group (Vietnamese)
      - 8. Vietnamese song, Saigon group (Vietnamese)
      - 9. "Clementine," Saigon group (Vietnamese)
      - 10. "Planting Rice," Saigon group (Vietnamese and Tagalog)
      - 11. "Red River Valley," Saigon group (Vietnamese)
      - 12. "Oh Susannah," Saigon group (Vietnamese, with English chorus)
      - 13. "Silent Night," group (English)
      - 14. "Dinah Blow Your Horn," group (English)
      - 15. Vietnamese song, Saigon group (Vietnamese)
      - 16. "We Shall Overcome," Saigon group (Vietnamese and English)
    - Tape 44, Vietnam, 1967 October 25
      This is a continuation from tape 43.
      - 1. "All My Trials," woman (English)
      - 2. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy and group (Vietnamese)
      - 3. "Michael Row the Boat Ashore," Pham Duy and group (English)
      - 4. "This Land Is Your Land," woman (English)
      - 5. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy and group (Vietnamese)
      - 6. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy and group (Vietnamese)
      - 7. "Rain on the Leaves," Pham Duy and group (English and Vietnamese)
      - 8. "Vietnam, Vietnam," Pham Duy and group (Vietnamese)
      - 9. "The Wounded Soldier," Pham Duy and group (Vietnamese)
      - 10. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy and group (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 45, Vietnam, 1967 November 1 (Box 88)
      Use copy reference number: 80116_a_0000245_a01
      This is a recording of a "Vietnamese Youth Choral Group" recorded at 194 Cong Ly. It includes music of two young Vietnamese composers. It was taped at the time of the first national elections held under the new Constitution, which had been written by the Constituent Assembly. Two of the political observers who had come at President Johnson's invitation were staying at General Lansdale's quarters. One of them, Robert Coate, was chairman of the Democratic Party for northern California. The other observer, Bill Connell, was executive officer for Vice President Humphrey. General Lansdale's nephew, Bill Lansdale, happened to be there at the same time (he was just beginning a tour of duty in Vietnam as a seaman in the Navy). The singers were from the Buddhist University in Saigon, who had stopped by to say hello.
      The list of participants includes: Trinh Cong Son and Nguyen Duc Quang (composers and singers); Tran Dai Loc (teacher, southern Buddhist); Le Dinh Dieu and Mrs. Dieu (teachers); Do Ngoc Yen (announcer); Pham Phu Minh (teacher, central Vietnam); Phan Van Phung (teacher, Buddhist movement); Do Anh Tai (teacher), and Nguyen Huu Dang (architect).
      This recording is continued on tape 46.
      - 1. "Hat Hoi Trang Ram," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 2. "We Shall Overcome," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 3. "A Long Day in Our Country," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 4. "War Sounds in the Night," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 5. "The Ballad of an Insane Girl," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 6. "The Fortune of My Mother," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 7. "The Wail of the Oxen," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 8. Song about Hanoi, Colonel Dinh (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 46, Vietnam, 1967 November 1
      This is a continuation from tape 45.
      - 1. "Joining the Army," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 2. "Lansdale," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 3. "Vietnam, the Bridegroom," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 4. "The Dawn," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 5. Song about unification of Vietnam, Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 6. A cadre song, Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 7. A cadre song, Youth Group (Vietnamese)
        At this point there is a long discussion concerning the problem of dwelling in the past versus moving ahead to the challenges of the future.
      - 8. Vietnamese song, Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 9. "Hope Rises Again," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
      - 10. "Vietnam, Vietnam," Youth Group (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 47, Vietnam, 1968 June 14
      This tape is entitled "Vietnamese Farewell Serenade." It was recorded at 194 Cong Ly. The group recorded on tape 45 had come to say goodbye to Lansdale on his last evening in Saigon. According to Lansdale, the group stayed for dinner (cleaning out his refrigerator) and remained past curfew. They were driven home by Admiral Veth, who had also stopped in to say goodbye. As they left, they sang "Goodbye Ed Lansdale," adding the names of the last remaining members of the SLO: "Cal" for Cal Mehlert, "Dave" for Dave Hudson, and "Charlie" for Charlie Sweet.
      The songs are all in Vietnamese. Most are performed by a female soloist, accompanied by the group.
    - Tape 48, Vietnam, 196? August 12
      This tape was made on August 12, "After VAA Hootenany," at 194 Cong Ly. No year is given, though this tape must have been made either in 1966 or 1967. Two of the participants -- Miss Pham Thai Thanh and Mr. Nghem Phu Phat -- are from a group called the "Nguon Song Group."
      - 1. "Suc May Ma Buon," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 2. "Ra Khoi" ("Let's Sail to the Ocean"), Miss Pham Thai Thanh Lan (Vietnamese)
      - 3. "A Guy Is a Guy," Miss Pham Thai Thanh Lan (English)
      - 4. "I'm Gonna Leave on the Morning Train," Steve Addis (English)
      - 5. "In Your Hand," Steve Addis and "Arthur" (no last name given) (English)
      - 6. "It's the Last Thing on My Mind," Steve Addis and Arthur (English)
      - 7. "Plaisir d'Amour," Pham Duy, Arthur, Jane Pratt (English and French)
      - 8. Vietnamese song, Jane Pratt (Vietnamese)
      - 9. "Dirty Old Town," Steve Addis and Arthur (English)
      - 10. "Greensleeves," Arthur, Steve Addis, and Pham Duy (instrumental)
    - Tape 49, Vietnam, 196? February 11
      This is a recording of a February 11th "Tet Work Session." No year is given. Pham Duy, Steve Addis, Art Guilliano, Hank Redford, and The Villagers all sing. This is the first in a series of three tapes: 49, 50, and 51.
      - 1. Flamenco, Hank Redford
      - 2. "Danz Amoura" (flamenco), Hank Redford
      - 3. "Rose, Rose I Love You" (zither)
      - 4. "Vietnam, Vietnam" (zither and guitar)
      - 5. "Widow's Lament," Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese)
      - 6. Southern folk song, Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese)
      - 7. "On Behalf," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 8. Flamenco, Hank Redford
    - Tape 50, Vietnam, 196? February 11
      This is a continuation from tape 49.
      - 9. Flamenco, Hank Redford
      - 10. "Separation," Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese)
      - 11. "Song of Spring," Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese)
      - 12. "Suc May Ma Buon," Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese)
      - 13. "Many a Mile," Steve Addis and Art Guilliano (English)
      - 14. "To Sing Often Is Better than to Sing with a Good Voice," Pham Duy and The Villagers (Vietnamese)
      - 15. Vietnamese song, Miss Pham Lan (Vietnamese)
      - 16. "The End of the World," Miss Pham Lan (Vietnamese)
    - Tape 51, Vietnam
      This is a continuation from tapes 49 and 50.
      - 17. "The Wounded Soldier," Art Guilliano, Pham Duy, Steve Addis, and Thao (Vietnamese and English)
      - 18. "Hang Down Your Head Tom Dooley," Steve Addis and group (English)
      - 19. "Rambling Boy," Steve Addis and group (English)
      - 20. Vietnamese work song, Thao and Miss Pham Lan (Vietnamese)
      - 21. "Children's Song," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 22. "Vietnam, Vietnam," Pham Duy and group (Vietnamese)
        The second half of this tape is a recording of a television or radio show, with Steve Addis and Pham Duy.
      - 1. "The Wounded Soldier," Pham Duy and Steve Addis (Vietnamese and English)
      - 2. "Rain on the Leaves," Pham Duy and Steve Addis (Vietnamese and English)
      - 3. "Children's Song," Pham Duy and Steve Addis (Vietnamese and English)
    - Tape 52, Vietnam, circa 1966-1967
      This is a recording of Steve Addis and Pham Duy singing while floating on the Perfume River, in Hue (not at 194 Cong Ly). There is no date, but it must have been recorded in 1966 or 1967.
      - 1. "Rain on the Leaves," Steve Addis (Vietnamese and English)
      - 2. "Hush Now My Darling," Steve Addis (English)
      - 3. "Summertime," Steve Addis (English)
      - 4. "Plaisir d'Amour," Steve Addis (French and English)
      - 5. Vietnamese song, Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 6. "Widow's Lament," Pham Duy (Vietnamese)
      - 7. "Times Are Getting Hard," Steve Addis (English)
      - 8. Folk song, Steve Addis (English)
        The second part of this tape contains songs by Captain Hershel Gober.
      - 1. "Proud American," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 2. "Saigon Warrior," Hershel Gober (English)
      - 3. "Look Over My Shoulder," Hershel Gober (English)
    - Tape 53, Vietnam, undated
      This tape has three distinct parts: first, there is Mitch Miller's recorded version of "The Rain on the Leaves." Next are some songs by Pham Duy and Steve Addis, recorded at 194 Cong Ly in Saigon (no date). Finally, there are two songs by a Liberian singer, Sherman Brown.
      The songs by Sherman Brown were from Hank Miller, who had come to Vietnam from Liberia. He had been in charge of the Voice of America for Middle Africa. His wife, Anne, wrote the first song, inspired by the flight of Gemini 4. The other song is Sherman Brown's own.